all maps are lying to you and here's why
this is the map that I always use in my
videos which is a usual map for most of
us let's take the largest island in the
world Greenland and compare its size to
Africa we can see that they are almost
the same size but the real size of
Greenland is several times smaller than
Africa this is because our planet is
round and it is impossible to transfer
the surface of a sphere to a flat
surface without a series of distortions
it's called projection there are many
different types of projections Each of
which distorts the surface or is very
inconvenient to use that is why the most
optimal and usual option for us is
called the Mercator Projection it is
convenient for navigation and perception
allowing to keep the shape but breaking
proportions countries that are closer to
the Equator have more correct sizes and
proportions but the further from the
equator the more the count stretch
upwards and distort in scale here is a
visual example of what countries would
look like in real proportions countries
away from the equator are actually much
smaller than we see them on a map